Hello, my friends.
How to insert a note in a link, at least at the beginning.
Consider this link at least that contains two notes.
The first one at the address 1000 and the second is at 2000.
The first contains the data one one hundredth and the second contains the data 200.
If I need to insert in, you know, at the beginning by making and switching the addresses, so you
see guys that 1000 have a previous note contains none.
We switched the note null to 3000 that indicates their memory address of their newly inserted note.
OK, so this is the very important thing that we should take care that addresses switching the addresses
and linking the newly created note with the previous and the next note because they are doubly linked
lists.
So we need to take care about the previous and the next note to the newly created notes.
OK.
In order to do that, to do that in programming and see we create structured had equal to hack.
Don't worry, we will see everything in later on in coding and real in real program in Java.
And we are going to learn everything now in lectures and see.
So I hope you understand everything and write them down because they are very important.
So struck note had this is equal to hat, we are creating the reference to the hat.
Now I will create a method called at beginning.
It took into pretty meater and called Val and return void.
Now the struck note.
New note, Malak, size of anthrax.
We are reserving the memory and we are creating and you note this in your note.
Data equal to that.
So adding to the beginning we took, we pass into perimeter the van and this van, we are inserting
the new node.
So in our case, in the previous animation we have inserted in node that contains 300 as date.
So consider Val is equal to 300 in this example.
Now we need to check if this had equal equal to null, then insert the new node next, equal to null
and the new node, the previous equal to none.
Therefore, the head is equal to then you note that we have inserted.
Good recently.
OK.
So if we have a link, at least a double link at least that that is empty, then the newly created node
would be the had that referred to the next null equal to null and the previous to it equal to null.
It's very simple.
OK.
This is the case if there is an empty link, at least.
Now let's see if else, if we have another note.
If we have one node or more, so new node the previous equal to none.
So the previous two, then you node equal to none, make it equal to none because we are inserting then
you node into at the beginning.
So the previous of this newly created node would be null.
It's very simple.
Look up at the 3000, the newly created node that contains 300 as data.
The This is not it because we are inserting it at the beginning.
This is the logic.
This is the very important trick.
New node next equal to had.
So we have moved the head from one thousand and make it to the new node, the next equal to the head.
So, no, the beginning of the previous link at least, is equal to the next of the node that it is
newly inserted.
Then make had the previous equal to you note OK, then change the previous of the node equal of the
head that it was was in that link.
At least change it to the new node the previous game, and had equal to new node.
Now move the head cursor to the first note that we have insert.
Don't worry if you have any conflict, we will clarify everything and more animation and more details
in the next videos.
So how to insert a node in the link, at least at the end, we will see it.